[{"question": "What is a structure in C language.?", "option1": "A) A structure is a collection of elements that can be of same data type.", "option2": "B) A structure is a collection of elements that can be of different data type.", "option3": "C) Elements of a structure are called members.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "What is the size of a C structure.?", "option1": "A) C structure is always 128 bytes.", "option2": "B) Size of C structure is the total bytes of all elements of structure.", "option3": "C) Size of C structure is the size of largest element.", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "What is the output of C program with structures.?\nint main()\n{\n    structure hotel\n    {\n        int items;\n        char name[10];\n    }a;\n    strcpy(a.name, \"TAJ\");\n    a.items=10;\n    printf(\"%s\", a.name);\n    return 0;\n}\n", "option1": "A) TAJ", "option2": "B) Empty string", "option3": "C) Compiler error", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "C"}, {"question": "What is the output of C program.?\nint main()\n{\n    struct book\n    {\n        int pages;\n        char name[10];\n    }a;\n    a.pages=10;\n    strcpy(a.name,\"Cbasics\");\n    printf(\"%s=%d\", a.name,a.pages);\n    return 0;\n}\n", "option1": "A) empty string=10", "option2": "B) C=basics", "option3": "C) Cbasics=10", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "C"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about C structures.", "option1": "A) Structure elements can be initialized at the time of declaration.", "option2": "B) Structure members can not be initialized at the time of declaration", "option3": "C) Only integer members of structure can be initialized at the time of declaraion", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about C structure.?\nint main()\n{\n    struct ship\n    {\n\n    };\n    return 0;\n}\n", "option1": "A) It is wrong to define an empty structure", "option2": "B) Member variables can be added to a structure even after its first definition.", "option3": "C) There is no use of defining an empty structure", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "C"}, {"question": "What is the output of C program.?\nint main()\n{\n    struct ship\n    {\n        int size;\n        char color[10];\n    }boat1, boat2;\n    boat1.size=10;\n    boat2 = boat1;\n    printf(\"boat2=%d\",boat2.size);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) boat2=0", "option2": "B) boat2=-1", "option3": "C) boat2=10", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "C"}, {"question": "What is the output of C program with structures.?\nint main()\n{\n    struct ship\n    {\n        char color[10];\n    }boat1, boat2;\n    strcpy(boat1.color,\"RED\");\n    printf(\"%s \",boat1.color);\n    boat2 = boat1;\n    strcpy(boat2.color,\"YELLOW\");\n    printf(\"%s\",boat1.color);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) RED RED", "option2": "B) RED YELLOW", "option3": "C) YELLOW YELLOW", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "A"}, {"question": "What is the output of C program with structures.?\nint main()\n{\n    struct tree\n    {\n        int h;\n    }\n    struct tree tree1;\n    tree1.h=10;\n    printf(\"Height=%d\",tree1.h);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) Height=0", "option2": "B) Height=10", "option3": "C) Height=", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " Choose a correct statement about C structure elements.?", "option1": "A) Structure elements are stored on random free memory locations", "option2": "B) structure elements are stored in register memory locations", "option3": "C) structure elements are stored in contiguous memory locations", "option4": "D) None of the above.", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " A C Structure or User defined data type is also called.?", "option1": "A) Derived data type", "option2": "B) Secondary data type", "option3": "C) Aggregate data type", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What are the uses of C Structures.?", "option1": "A) structure is used to implement Linked Lists, Stack and Queue data structures", "option2": "B) Structures are used in Operating System functionality like Display and Input taking.", "option3": "C) Structure are used to exchange information with peripherals of PC", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program with structures.?\nint main()\n{\n    struct tree\n    {\n        int h;\n        int w;\n    };\n    struct tree tree1={10};\n    printf(\"%d \",tree1.w);\n    printf(\"%d\",tree1.h);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) 0 0", "option2": "B) 10 0", "option3": "C) 0 10", "option4": "D) 10 10", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program with structures.?\nint main()\n{\n    struct tree\n    {\n        int h;\n        int rate;\n    };\n    struct tree tree1={0};\n    printf(\"%d \",tree1.rate);\n    printf(\"%d\",tree1.h);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) 0 0", "option2": "B) -1 -1", "option3": "C) NULL NULL", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "A"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program.?\nint main()\n{\n    struct laptop\n    {\n        int cost;\n        char brand[10];\n    };\n    struct laptop L1={5000,\"ACER\"};\n    struct laptop L2={6000,\"IBM\"};\n    printf(\"Name=%s\",L1.brand);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) ACER", "option2": "B) IBM", "option3": "C) Compiler error", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "A"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program with structures pointers.?\nint main()\n{\n    struct forest\n    {\n        int trees;\n        int animals;\n    }F1,*F2;\n    F1.trees=1000;\n    F1.animals=20;\n    F2=&F1;\n    printf(\"%d \",F2.animals);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) 0", "option2": "B) 20", "option3": "C) Compiler error", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " What\nint main()\n{\n    struct bus\n    {\n        int seats;\n    }F1, *F2;\n    F1.seats=20;\n    F2=&F1;\n    F2->seats=15;\n    printf(\"%d \",F1.seats);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) 15", "option2": "B) 20", "option3": "C) 0", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "A"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program with structure arrays.?\nint main()\n{\n    struct pens\n    {\n        int color;\n    }p1[2];\n    struct pens p2[3];\n    p1[0].color=5;\n    p1[1].color=9;\n    printf(\"%d \",p1[0].color);\n    printf(\"%d\",p1[1].color);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) 5 5", "option2": "B) 5 9", "option3": "C) 9 5", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program with structure array pointers.?\nint main()\n{\n    struct car\n    {\n        int km;\n    }*p1[2];\n    struct car c1={1234};\n    p1[0]=&c1;\n    printf(\"%d \",p1[0]->km);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) 0", "option2": "B) 1", "option3": "C) 1234", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " Choose a correct statement about C structures.", "option1": "A) A structure can contain same structure type member.", "option2": "B) A structure size is limited by only physical memory of that PC.", "option3": "C) You can define an unlimited number of members inside a structure.", "option4": "D) All the above.", "ans": "D"}]
